TIEN PHAT NGUYEN

Address: 384 Elgar Rd, Box Hill, Victoria, 3128 • Mobile: 0432004403 Email: aaronng.dev@gmail.com • LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tien-phat-nguyen

CAREER PROFILE

First-year Bachelor of Data Science student after finishing two years of Bachelor of Information Technology with experience in Agile Scrum project management, problem-solving, learning new technologies, time management and excellent work responsibility. Eight months experienced working as a Backend Developer with a focus on PHP and NoSQL Databases and gained valuable insights into software development, database management, and server-side scripting

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Language: C/C++, PHP, Python, Javascript, Dart, HTML/CSS
- Framework: Laravel, Flutter, MVC
- · Database: MongoDB, MySQL
- Tools: Git, Agile development methodologies

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Data Science
Deakin University, Melbourne, Burwood

March 2023 - Present

Bachelor of Information Technology
Ho Chi Minh City University of Technology, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam

September 2019 - May 2022

EXPERIENCE

Green Mobile Application Corporation, Ho Chi Minh , Vietnam Intern Backend Developer

January 2022 - August 2022

- Collaborated with the UI team to develop and implement new APIs to upgrade project management and HR management capability of launching application
- Maintained and modified Excel data pipeline satisfied with customer demand
- Enhanced the performance of the API's backend codebase by optimizing the database queries, resulting in reduced response times at least 20%

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Solution Challenge, Ho Chi Minh, Vietnam *Leader*

January 2021 - March 2021

- Collaborated with 4 members to propose CALM Community Aware of Lifelong Medicare solution help people change lifestyle healthier. Flutter and Firebase are core of the project
- Distributed specific tasks to other members of the team and closely monitored progress, while utilizing Agile methodologies to manage the overall progress of the project

REFEREES

• Trung Duc Ha - Chief Technology Officer at Green Mobile Application Corporation